{
    "title": "The sources of energy for muscle contractions & creatine metabolism",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "1. Which of the following contractile protein of skeletal muscle involve in ATPase activity?",
        "options": ["Troponin", "Myosin", "Tubulin", "Tropomyosin"],
        "correct": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "2. when depletion of ATP in muscle occur, the fastest source of energy is:",
        "options": [
          "aerobic phosphorylation",
          "ATP-PCR system",
          "anaerobic glycolysis"
        ],
        "correct": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "3.the storage form of energy in muscles:",
        "options": ["ATP", "glucose", "creatine"],
        "correct": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "4.What is the primary function of creatine phosphate (CP) in muscle cells?",
        "options": [
          "Acting as a substrate for aerobic phosphorylation",
          "Facilitating the conversion of pyruvate to lactate",
          "Serving as an energy buffer to prevent rapid ATP depletion",
          "Promoting the synthesis of glucose via gluconeogenesis"
        ],
        "correct": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "5.Organ involved in creatine metabolism:",
        "options": ["kidney", "liver", "muscle", "all"],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "6.Amino acids ..... are responsible for creatine synthesis",
        "options": [
          "glycine + arginine",
          "alanine + pyruvate",
          "Methionine",
          "A & C"
        ],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "7. Which enzyme is responsible for the synthesis of creatine from guanidoacetate in the liver?",
        "options": [
          "Creatine kinase",
          "Arginine glycine transamidinase",
          "Lactate dehydrogenase",
          "Guanidoacetate methyl transferase"
        ],
        "correct": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "8. Which cycle is responsible for the conversion of lactate to pyruvate in the liver, ultimately leading to glucose synthesis?",
        "options": [
          "Cori cycle",
          "Glycolysis cycle",
          "Glucose-alanine cycle",
          "Krebs cycle"
        ],
        "correct": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "9. What is the primary function of aerobic phosphorylation in muscle metabolism?",
        "options": [
          "To produce lactate from pyruvate",
          "To regenerate creatine from creatinine",
          "To generate ATP from pyruvate and acetyl-CoA",
          "To convert glucose to glycogen for storage"
        ],
        "correct": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "10. Which energy system is characterized by being half as fast as ATP-PCr but 2-3 times faster than aerobic metabolism?",
        "options": [
          "Anaerobic glycolysis",
          "ATP-PCr system",
          "Aerobic phosphorylation",
          "Calcium ion cycling"
        ],
        "correct": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "22. The immediate source for ATP rebuilding during muscle contraction is:",
        "options": [
          "anaerobic glycolysis",
          "aerobic phosphorylation",
          "ATP-PCr system",
          "non of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "23. Organs that involved in creatine metabolism are:",
        "options": ["kidney", "liver", "muscle", "all of the above"],
        "correct": 3
      }
    ]
  }
